Hi, I'm Kyle from Vital Pet Life.
One thing we learned pretty quickly as sellers is that discounts can become a bad habit.
It's very easy to start offering coupons everywhere, and then suddenly realize you train customers
to only buy when something's on sale.
That's why we started using Amazon's brand tailored promotions.
Instead of discounting for every shopper on Amazon, this tool lets you create promotions,
specifically for customers who've already interacted with your brand.
One thing we learned pretty quickly is that you can find brand tailored promotions under
the advertising menu.
This page lets you create targeted promotions for different types of customers who already
have some connection with your brand.
Big idea here is targeting.
Instead of offering a discount to everyone browsing Amazon, you can focus on shoppers who
are more likely to buy, like customers who previously purchased from your brand, or people
who have shown interest.
Here you can see the different goals you can choose from.
For example, you can target new customers, current customers, and customers who purchase
your other products.
This tool is really about encouraging new purchases and building long-term customer
relationships.
Sometimes we'll use these promotions to bring back past purchasers, introduce customers to
another product in a catalog, or support a brand new product launch.
After choosing your goal, you select the products you want to promote, and then choose the specific
audience to target.
The nice thing about targeted promotions is that you usually don't need huge discounts.
Because the offer is going to a more relevant audience, smaller promotions can still drive
strong results while helping protect their margins.
Broad promotions and coupons still have their place, but targeted offers like this can often
lead to more sustainable growth.
So if you're trying to build a brand on Amazon and encourage repeat customers, brand tailored
promotions are definitely worth exploring.